# William F. Slavney

650 East Parkway South Memphis, TN 38104 (901) 321-3111 wslavney@cbu.edu

**PRIMARY EXPERTISE:** Practical Theology with a concentration on Catholic morality and ethical teachings of the Church. **SECONDARY EXPERTISE:** Systematic Theology with concentrations in Catholic spirituality, Christology, and Ecclesiology.

EDUCATION	
CHRISTIAN BROTHERS UNIVERSITY  B.S. Chemistry Candidate (Expected graduation May 2023)	Memphis, TN
CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA Ph.D. Moral Theology/Ethics Candidate (Expected Graduation May 2020)	Washington, DC, DC
UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE M.S. Nursing (2020)	Memphis, TN
UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE  B.S. Nursing with Medical License (2019)	Memphis, TN
AQUINAS COLLEGE M.A. Sacred Theology (2016)	Nashville, TN
AQUINAS COLLEGE B.A. Theology (2014)	Nashville, TN
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	
Christian Brothers High School Part Time Campus Minister	Memphis, TN Oct 2019 – Present
Saint Francis Hospital Part Time Emergency Multisystem Trauma Nurse	<b>Memphis, TN</b> Apr 2019 – Present
Christian Brothers University Adjunct Instructor of Biology	<b>Memphis, TN</b> Oct 2020 – Present
Assistant to Health Services	Aug 2020 – Present
Director of Catholic Identity	Jan 2019 – Present
Professor of Religion and Philosophy	Jan 2019 – Present
Campus Ministry Associate	Aug 2018 – Present
Adjunct Professor of Religious Studies	Jan 2015 – Dec 2018
Catholic University of America Visiting Assistant Professor of Catholic Theology	Washington, DC, DC May 2018 – Aug 2018

*May 2018 – Aug 2018* 

## **College of Holy Cross**

Visiting Adjunct Professor of Religious Studies

**Worchester, MA** *May* 2017 – *Aug* 2017 *May* 2016 – *Aug* 2016

#### **CREDENTIALS & LICENCES**

- (S.T.L) Licentiate in Moral Theology and Ethics
- American Red Cross Certified Lifeguard
- (R.N. & L.P.N.) Medical License TN
- (E.M.T) Emergency Medical Technician TN

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### **Christian Brothers University**

- RS 200 Understanding Religion
- RS 217 Old Testament
- RS 218 New Testament
- RS 220 History of Christian Thought: to the Reformation
- RS 221 History of Christian Thought: since the Reformation
- RS 230 Christian Ethics
- RS 245 Honors Religion and Science
- RS 254 Christianity and Peace
- RS 270 World Religions
- RS 280 Catholicism
- RS 285 The Church in the World
- RS 300 Jesus Christ
- RS 320 Religion in America
- RS 324 Christian Spirituality
- RS 330 Justice and Society
- RS 331 Spirituality of Ethics and Eating
- RS 340 African American Theology
- RS 345 God, Evil, and Suffering
- RS 355 Judaism
- RS 372 Women and Christianity
- RS 377 Apocalyptic Imagination
- RS 380 Paul: His Life and Letters
- RS 385 The Gospels
- RS 420 Catholic Spirituality
- RS 460 Moral Theology
- PHIL 201 Introduction to Logic
- PHIL 220 Contemporary Moral Issues
- PHIL 223 Business Ethics
- PHIL 317 Ancient Philosophy
- PHIL 318 Modern Philosophy
- PHIL 322 Medical Ethics

Memphis, TN

#### **Catholic University of America**

#### TRS 357 Catechesis

### **College of the Holy Cross**

Worchester, MA

- RELS 101 Introduction to the Comparative Study of Religion
- RELS 102 Mary in Christian Theology
- RELS 114 Introduction to Theology
- RELS 115 Angels and Demons
- RELS 116 Catholicism
- RELS 139 Understanding Jesus
- RELS 141 Contemporary Christian Morality
- RELS 143 Social Ethics
- RELS 147 Judaism
- RELS 149 Judaism in the Time of Jesus
- RELS 190 History of the Early Church
- RELS 203 Death & Afterlife
- RELS 219 Christian Prayer in Theory in Practice
- RELS 230 Theological Perspectives on Medical Ethics
- RELS 284 Sex, Money, Power, and the Bible

# **REFERENCES**

available upon request.